# **Aleksandar Nikolic**

Front-End Developer

## Profile

Passionate web developer who strives to write clean and functional code with added focus on accessibility, responsiveness, and user experience. Flourishes in fast-paced, competitive, and team based environments where he can continually learn and grow. Please visit <a href="https://imaleks.dev/">https://imaleks.dev/</a> for a look at my portfolio

# Employment History

# Web Development Volunteer at ShopHere, Toronto

May 2020 — Present

Partnering with ShopHERE and Shopify - building simple Shopify websites and tools to help Toronto businesses affected by the global COVID19 crisis

## Bartender at St. Regis & Terroni Group & Oretta, Toronto

June 2016 — February 2020

Previously enjoyed employment as a bartender in the fine-dining industry in the downtown Toronto core.

Most recently helped open the St. Regis, Toronto where I worked dynamically between the two different dining restaurants available in the hotel

Personally helped prepare seasonal cocktail menu changes and organize complex events (TIFF, NBA Championship) while serving a high volume of upscale clientele and maintaining strict brand standards

#### Education

# Web Development Immersive Program, Juno College, Toronto

October 2019 — May 2020

Graduated from Juno College's immersive full-time bootcamp as well as their part-time web development course

Participated in simulated design agency environments including Git workflow, stand-ups, and design collaboration. Built a deep understanding of core front-end languages (HTML, CSS, JavaScript) as well as industry-wide libraries and frameworks (React, jQuery, Node.js)

#### Various Programs, Udemy

January 2019 — Present

An ongoing learning experience consisting of core front-end languages and tools taught by industry professionals and experts

## Bachelor of Liberal Arts: Sociology, York University, Toronto

September 2013 — June 2015

### Bachelor of Applied Arts: Paralegal Studies, Humber College, Toronto

September 2009 — June 2013

#### **Details**

384 Manning Avenue, Toronto, M6G 2V7, Canada, (416) 529-7181 nikolic.aleks90@gmail.com

#### Links

Personal

LinkedIn

GitHub

Medium

**Twitter** 

#### **Skills**

HTML

CSS3

JavaScript

jQuery

React

Node.js

Git/GitHub/Git Workflow

**Terminal** 

#### Languages

English

Serbo-Croatian